

Alessandro Bagnoli

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · BACKENI

Riccione (RN), Italy

□ (+39) 3391580201 | 🗷 alessandro.bagnoli4@gmail.com | 🖸 AlessandroBagnoli | 🛅 alessandro-bagnoli

"Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic."

Summary.

Currently Backend Engineer at Alpian. 4+ of years experience in backend development on Java environments and frameworks, with curiosity in exploring also the infrastructural side of the solutions I work on. Interested in devising and applying better methods of solving challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools on the backend side when needed.

Work Experience ____

Alpian Riccione (RN), Italy - Full remote

Backend Engineer May 2022 - Today

Member of a Scrum Team building the backend side of the first Swiss digital private bank, leveraging microservices architecture and fully embracing the cloud native approach using GCP.

- Languages and tools: Java 11, Kotlin, Go, Maven
- Frameworks: Spring Boot, Hibernate
- Databases: both relational (PostgreSQL) and non-relational (MongoDB, Google Datastore)
- Testing libs and frameworks: JUnit, Mockito, Testcontainers
- Communication: both synchronous (REST, gRPC), and asynchronous (Google Pub/Sub, ActiveMQ)
- Versioning: Git with Github-Flow

OverIT Riccione (RN), Italy - Full remote

BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

October 2021 - May 2022

Backend Development and maintenance of custom web applications exposing APIs consumed both from an enterprise BPM and web frontend.

- Languages and tools: Java 8, Maven, WildFly
- Frameworks: Spring Framework, Hibernate
- Databases: relational (PostgreSQL)
- Testing libs and frameworks: JUnit, Mockito
- Communication: both synchronous (REST), and asynchronous (ActiveMQ)
- Versioning: Git with Git-Flow

I-Tel Riccione (RN), Italy

BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

August 2018 - October 2021

Design and implementation of custom projects and middlewares required for integration with external backend systems. Migration of one of the company's products from a proprietary development platform to a new modular architecture, based on well-known frameworks.

- Languages and tools: Java 8/11, Tomcat, Asterisk
- Frameworks: Spring Boot, Hibernate
- Databases: relational (PostgreSQL)
- Communication: synchronous (REST)
- · Versioning: Git, SVN

Education

Alma Mater Studiorum - Università di Bologna

Cesena (FC), Italia

MASTER'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

September 2012 - July 2018

Certifications

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

CREDENTIAL ID: EC7RD6TJEJ411W59